Goal setting is everywhere around us.
By this point in your life,
you've probably set various goals:
exercise three times a week,
meet your quarterly targets at work,
learn a new language.
You've also probably experienced how setting intentions
for yourself improves the likelihood that you'll make those things happen.
What you might not know is that one of the areas
in which this is most true is learning.
Whether you're leading a team for the first time
or joining a challenging project,
countless studies have shown
that setting a clear learning intention
can make the learning process
more efficient, fun, and successful.
And yet there are three big things that hold
many of us back when it comes to learning.
One is that we often focus more on a specific performance goal
when we should be focusing on the learning journey itself.
In addition, we often set learning intentions
that are not actually meaningful for us.
We'll talk more about those two ideas later.
But the biggest mistake of all is that we often
just don't take the time to set any kind of intention.
So why does the mere act of setting intentions
have such a great impact on learning?
It's simple, really.
Our brains only have so much attention they can give.
We live in a complex world with more stimuli
than we can possibly process.
Being purposeful with intentions helps us to cut through the noise
and stay focused on what we've identified as personally important.
This focus helps us not only to envision a final outcome,
but also to navigate the learning journey,
evaluating and changing course as needed.
When you inevitably face a challenge, or don't succeed
the first or second or third time,
that energy you focused on your intention will help you
find a way through that challenge and to continue onwards.
And along the way, you'll be more likely
to enjoy the journey itself.
So, whether you're learning a new technical skill
or learning to be a better manager,
setting learning intentions will help you realize your vision,
improve your experience, and make it meaningful,
which makes the learning even more powerful.